# **ADURA ANSA**

240-615-2748

✓ aduragbemiansa@gmail.com

Maryland

aduraaansa.com

### PROFILE

I have proficient skills in understanding the nature of human perception and action through extensive research and analyzation. Determined to apply the skills and knowledge I have gained as a UI/UX designer & researcher, and as a front-end coder to create quality content for users. Observation, inspiration, and discipline are my foundation for success.

#### SKILLS & TOOLS

- Canva
- CSS
- HTML
- Figma
- · Web Design
- Visual Design
- User Research
- User Interface Design
- Responsive Design
- Wireframe Creation
- · Problem-Solving
- Strong Communication

### Completed 35 hours of web programming

- Completed 35 hours of web programming tasks each week to learn technological skills and coding languages
- Created replica of the Google landing page utilizing HTML& CSS.
- Applied programming languages to design and build responsive portfolio website

### EDUCATION

# THE CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA | B.A.

Psychology

Aug 2016- May 2020

Washington, D.C.

### HOBBIES

- Drawing
- Reading
- Creative Writing

## EXPERIENCE

#### UI/UX DESIGN & RESEARCH | Jan 2022- present

- Completed a 15+ week study plan of UI/UX design & research, by utilizing online resources to gain essential knowledge, and to acquire practical skills
- Developed critical design thinking skills that enabled me to create mockups and designs to solve problems
- Concentrated on how to begin UX design process, through which I learned how to empathize with users particularly when conducting user research
- Created website and mobile app wireframes for projects

FRONT-END CODING | Nov 2021 - present

## PSYCHOLOGY RESEARCHER | Aug 2016 - May 2020

- Developed an understanding of human behavior through extensive research and analyzing behavioral data.
- Designed an experiment to study how time of day affects students' usage of phones, when interacting with friends
- Conducted scientific research that required me to uphold the standards and ethics of the research method utilized in the study
- Acquired proficiency in interpreting and collecting data to understand the cause and effect between variables
- Collaborated with fellow students to conduct research; we successfully identified methods and approaches that enabled us to procure valid and reliable results